Captain?
（ミミ･パールバトン）
団… 長？
How?
（隊員Ａ）何で…
It's all over...
（隊員Ｂ）おしまいだ
（隊員Ｃ）殺される…
We're dead.
Don't let it swallow him!
（ナツキ･スバル）
飲み込ませるな！
If we free him before he gets swallowed, we can save him!
腹に飲み込まれる
前なら―
まだ
助け出せるはずだ！
Subaru-kun...
（レム）スバルくん
Don't think a little bit of despair
is enough to stop me!
このくらいの絶望で―
俺が止まると思うなよ
Giving up doesn't suit us!
諦めるのは
似合わねえ 俺も―
Not me, not you!
お前も―
Not any of us!
誰にでも！
Let's go, Patrasche!
行くぜ パトラッシュ
鯨の鼻先で回れ！
Run right under the Whale's nose!
The only one who may sniff Subaru-kun is me!
スバルくんのにおいを嗅ぐのは
レムの特権です！
Close your mouth!
（クルシュ･カルステン）
口を閉じろ！
At a glance, the situation looks dismal.
一見して 事態は最悪にあるな
Where is Wilhelm?
ヴィルヘルムは？
If you remember him,
（スバル）
あんたが覚えてるってことは
少なくとも 霧に消されちゃいねえ
at least we know the fog hasn't erased him.
Everything depends on how well Rem fights.
レムの奮戦しだいってとこだ
What do you think, Natsuki Subaru?
（クルシュ）
どう見る ナツキ･スバル
おかしいとは思わないか？
Does nothing seem strange to you?
Strange?
（スバル）おかしい？
There are now three White Whales.
（クルシュ）
白鯨が３体に増えた
If it is actually a witchfiend that lives in a group,
how could we not know that by now?
仮に 群れをなす
魔獣だとしたら―
それが伝わっていないことなど
あるものか
There must be some trick behind it.
何か カラクリがあるはずだ
And we need to find out what that is, huh?
（スバル）
それを見つけろってことか
If we don't, we won't hold out very long.
（クルシュ）
でなければ 長くはもたない
何とかするぞ
We have to do something.
Retreat is no longer an option.
撤退など もはや
選択肢にないのだから
Fire!
放て！
"Fire," I said!
放つんだ！
Crusch-san!
（スバル）クルシュさん！
Willpower!
根性ー！
Damn... Being a daredevil isn't enough!
クソッ
命張ってるばっかじゃねえぞ
頭回せ！ 何で いきなり３体に…
I've gotta use my head!
Why are there three of them?
Duck!
（クルシュ）よけろ！
Whoa!
Awesome!
すっげー！
We'll all back up Natsuki-san and Crusch-san
（ヘータロー･パールバトン）
みんなで ナツキさんと
クルシュさんを援護します
until the captain is fully healed,
and we can regroup.
団長の回復が済んで
隊長を立て直すまで
Ricardo's still alive?
リカードの奴 生きてるのか！
Yes, my sister took him to Felix-san.
（ヘータロー）
はい　先ほど お姉ちゃんが―
フェリックスさんのもとへ
連れて行きました
He struggled a lot! It wasn't easy!
（ミミ）暴れて大変だった
Gotcha... That's a relief.
そっか よかった
On the verge of death,
our captain sent a message.
（ヘータロー）
瀕(ひん)死の団長から 伝言があります
"Hey, it's gettin' a lot lighter.
“なんや 軽うなっとるで”
The fact that I didn't die proves that!"
“ワイが死ななかったんが
その証拠や！”
That's what he said.
だそうです
"Lighter"?
軽く？
What's light about a hard,
heavy situation like this?
この ヘビーで
ベリーハードな状況で―
何が軽いって…
Light?
軽い？
That's it... I get it!
そうか そうだったのかよ！
Huh?
What?
（隊員）何だ？
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
おわーっ！
ぐわーっ！
Wilhelm-san!
ヴィルヘルムさん！
I still have much to learn.
未熟… 油断を…
I was careless...
Is he all right!?
（ヘータロー）無事ですか！
Yeah, he's just unconscious!
（スバル）
ああ 気を失ってるだけだ
Sorry, but could you take him to Ferris?
悪(わり)いが フェリスんとこまで
頼めるか？
Of course! What about you?
はい！ ナツキさんは？
I realized something...
気づいたことがあんだよ
（隊員）
うおー！ てやーっ！
It divided?
（クルシュ）
分裂しているだと？
Yeah.
（スバル）
ああ ヴィルヘルムさんが
えぐり取った左目と―
Its fighting strength and the left eye that
Wilhelm-san gouged out have me convinced.
戦闘力が根拠だ
Your group's been fighting it head-on, so you must have noticed it.
直接やり合ってる
クルシュさんたちのほうが―
それは感じてるだろ
レムは無我夢中でしたけど 確かに
I was absorbed in battle, but...
You're right.
I do agree with your conjecture that these ones
are weaker than the first one we engaged.
奴が もとの１体より弱っている
という推測には同意だ
But what good does knowing this do?
だが それを理解したところで
どうする
Killing three White Whales
is much easier said than done.
３体の白鯨を殺す
口で言うのは安いが 高い壁だ
We don't need to kill all three of them.
３匹も殺す必要ねえよ
１匹だけでいいはずだ
Just one should be enough.
That bastard's been making
its two doubles fight,
分身２匹に ビシバシ戦わせて―
while it hangs around up there, watching.
高みの見物決め込んでやがる
あの野郎は―
What, exactly, do you think it's doing that for?
一体 何をしてるんだと思う？
That is the real one?
奴が本体か
It won't come down because it knows
that it can't let itself be killed.
（スバル）
下りてこねえのは―
自分がやられるわけには
いかねえからだと思う
But...
だが―
I cannot rely on my sword
to hit from this distance.
私の剣も この距離では
期待できない
If I had one strike, it might be possible...
一太刀ならば あるいはと思うが
I've got a plan.
ちょっとばかし―
It's honestly a pretty big gamble, though.
賭けの要素が強すぎる
作戦があるけど―
You want in?
乗るか？
I think you're insane.
（クルシュ）
正気とは思えんな
We're insane for taking on
that huge thing in the first place.
もともと あんなでけえ奴を
狩ろうって時点で―
正気じゃねえだろ
Perhaps.
そうだな　いや そうだった
No, you are correct.
That goes for everyone here right now.
この場にいる全員が
そのはずだった
Get away!
（隊員）離れろ！
We will hold off the two doubles.
２体は 我々が引き受ける
I'm in. I will take your gamble.
その賭けに乗ろう
They're coming this way...
（隊員Ａ）こっちに来るぞ
Stay away!
（隊員Ｂ）来るな
Run!
（隊員Ｃ）逃げろ！
We'll be wiped out...
（隊員Ｄ）全滅だ…
Crusch-sama!
（隊員）クルシュ様
Stand up! Lift your heads!
立て！ 顔を上げろ！ 武器を持て！
Take up your weapons!
Look at that boy.
あの男を見ろ
He's so weak and fragile, a breath
could blow him away, and he's unarmed!
あれは武器もなく非力で
吹けば飛ぶような 弱者だ！
打ち倒されるところを
私も この目で見た無力な男だ
He is a powerless boy, whose defeat
I have seen with my own eyes!
He's weaker than anyone else here!
ほかの誰よりも
あの男が１番弱い
Yet he's shouting louder than anyone
そんな男が まだやれると―
that we can still do this.
誰よりもほえている
それでどうして
我らが下を向いていられる
So how can we sit here, staring at the ground?
If our weakest man has not given up,
最も弱い男が
諦めていないのに―
how can we bow down and accept defeat?
どうして 我らに
ひざを折ることが許される！
Did you all come this far
卿(けい)らは 恥に溺れるために―
to wallow in your own shame!?
ここまで来たのか！
Charge!
続け！
She has some nerve,
calling me a weakling and a loser...
弱者だの 負け犬だの
好き放題言ってくれやがって
Let's do this, Rem.
やるぞ レム
Time for the climax!
見せ場だ！
Right, Subaru-kun.
はい スバルくん
Al Huma!
アルヒューマ！
Please!
お願い！
I'm counting on you.
頼んだぞ
Hey... Now that I see you up close,
you're one creepy looking bastard, aren't you?
（スバル）
よう こうして間近で見ると
超気持ち悪いな お前
Try to keep up with me.
ついてこいや
Just so you know, I'm notorious for being
so annoying that no one can ignore me!
言っとくが 俺は
シカトできねえほど―
ウザさに定評のある男だぜ
Okay, let's do this!
んじゃ いっちょいくか
I'm doing you a huge favor! Listen up!
大サービスだ よく聞けやー！
It's because of you that Rem died
てめえのせいで レムが死んで―
and I experienced such a horrible trauma!
俺は すんげえトラウマ
背負ったぞ コラ！
I made it back!
戻ってきたー！
Rem!
レム！
Yes!
はい！
You saved me.
助かった
Thank you for the treat.
（レム）
ごちそうさまです
What are you talking about?
何 言ってんの
Don't let me down, Patrasche.
頼むぜ パトラッシュ
You're a dragon, aren't you?
ドラゴンなんだろ？
かっこいいとこ見せてくれ！
Show me how awesome you are!
Take this!
食らいやがれ！
Fire!
（クルシュ）放てー！
This is for my wife, Theresia van Astrea.
我が妻
テレシア･ヴァン･アストレアに捧(ささ)ぐ
I win.
（ヴィルヘルム）俺の勝ちだ
As a weaker swordsman, you no longer
have reason to hold a sword.
俺より弱い お前に
剣を持つ理由はもうない
If I don't hold it, who will?
私が持たないなら 誰が…
I shall inherit your reason
for taking up the sword.
お前が剣を振る理由は 俺が継ぐ
You need but
お前は―
become my reason for taking it up.
俺が剣を振る理由になればいい
Hey, do you like flowers?
（テレシア）
ねえ 花は 好き？
I don't hate them anymore.
（ヴィルヘルム）
嫌いじゃなくなった
Why do you take up the sword?
どうして 剣を振るの？
（ヴィルヘルム）お前を―
I take it up...
守るために
to protect you.
Do you love me?
私のこと 愛してる？
You know that.
分かれ
I still want to hear you say it sometimes.
言葉にしてほしいことだって
あるのよ
Very well.
ああ いつか―
Someday...
When I feel like it.
気が向いた時にな
てやーっ！
Sleep for all eternity.
眠れ　永久(とこしえ)に
It is finished, Theresia.
終わったぞ テレシア
At last...
やっと
Theresia, I...
テレシア 私は…
俺は―
I...
I love you!
お前を―
愛している
The White Whale has fallen!
ここに白鯨は沈んだ！
The witchfiend of fog,
400年の歳月を生き―
which has terrorized the world for four centuries,
世界を脅かしてきた 霧の魔獣
has been struck down by Wilhelm van Astrea!
ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレアが―
討ちとったり！
This battle is our victory!
この戦い 我らの勝利だ！
（クルシュ）
大丈夫か？ ナツキ･スバル
Are you all right, Natsuki Subaru?
（スバル）
どうにか こうにかな
Somehow or another...
I'm glad you're also safe, Crusch-san.
クルシュさんも
無事そうで 何よりだ
（クルシュ）私はな
I am, yes.
But our losses are not few.
だが 皆の消耗は少なくない
Even with the White Whale's defeat,
白鯨を討ってなお
消えた者たちは戻らないのだから
those who have vanished will not return.
I think you did great, Crusch-san.
クルシュさんは
よくやったと思うぜ
Your popularity should shoot through the—
これで ますます好感度が…
って あれ？
Wait, did I just give you a boost
in the royal selection that I shouldn't have?
ひょっとして 王選じゃ
結構まずい後押ししてねえ？
That is quite a gloomy look on your face.
随分と 暗い顔をするものだな
You don't look like the hero who
brought down the White Whale.
白鯨を落とした
英雄の顔には見えん
The first thing Emilia-tan's
gonna do is call me a traitor...
（スバル）
エミリアたんに 開口一番
裏切り者って罵られ… ええっ
Wait, what did you just call me?
今 何て言った？
白鯨を落とした英雄だ
The hero who brought down the White Whale.
卿の功績を―
I would not wish to be
そのまま全て 当家の
手柄にするほど―
shameless enough to claim
your achievement as my own.
恥知らずではありたくない
あっ いや 俺は
そんなたいしたこと…
No, I really didn't do anything.
It sounds like your opinion
of me has improved a lot.
随分と 評価が
改善されたみたいで 驚きだよ
I'm surprised.
There is no cause for modesty.
謙遜することはない
本来ならば その功績―
In truth, I would love to welcome you
当家に迎え入れて 相応に
報いたいところではあるが
into my household and reward
your accomplishments.
Please don't ask that of me!
それは勘弁してくれ
忠誠とも忠義とも違うけど―
It isn't about loyalty or allegiance,
but my faith already lies
exactly where it should.
俺の信頼は もう
預けるべきところに預けてある
俺は エミリアを王にするよ
I'll make Emilia the ruler.
誰のためでもなく
俺がそれをしたいんだ
Not for anyone's sake.
It's simply what I want to do.
I was already aware of that,
分かっていたことだが
それなりに こたえるものだな
but it still stings a bit.
Honestly, I think you're an amazing person.
クルシュさんは
すげえ人だと思うぜ
If I'd been on my own, I'm pretty sure
I'd have accepted your offer.
俺だって １人なら間違いなく
その手をとってたと思う
I'll be counting on you to uphold the alliance.
同盟の件は よろしく頼むよ
Even if we end up as enemies,
最終的に
敵対することになっても―
I believe we can get along until then.
それまでは きっと
仲よくやっていこうぜ
ナツキ･スバル
１つ考えを正そう
Natsuki Subaru, allow me
to correct one idea you have.
Even if we do find ourselves in conflict one day,
雌雄を決する機会が
きたとしても―
I shall remain friendly toward you.
私は卿に対して 友好的であろう
いずれ必ず来たる
決別の日にあっても―
Even if the day where me must settle things comes upon us,
今日の日の卿への恩義を
私は忘れまい
I shall not forget the debt
I have incurred this day.
故に 敵対する時が来たとて―
Therefore, even if we do become enemies,
私は 卿に最後まで―
I shall respect and show you favor until the end.
敬意を払い 友好的である
If I hadn't already had a number one
and two in my heart,
俺の心の１番目と２番目が
埋まってなかったら―
I would've been in trouble there.
かなり危ないところだった
フン
女として 卿をどうこういう
ところまでは考えていない
I have not gone so far as to think of you as a woman might.
いくらか琴線に触れる場面が
ないではなかったが―
I do not deny there were occasions
on which my heartstrings felt a pull,
but my heart lies at the end of my dream.
私の心は 夢の果てに預けてある
さて―
Now...
私は このまま―
I shall leave to take our wounded
and the White Whale's carcass to the capital.
負傷者と白鯨の屍(しかばね)を
王都へ運びたいところだが
卿には未だ 何か使命が
残っているようだな
But it would appear you still
have a duty to attend to.
Yeah.
ああ 言っちゃ悪いが―
It may sound rude,
but in a sense, that's what
this whale hunt was really about.
ある意味じゃ それを
やってのけるための鯨狩りだ
Oh?
ほう この白鯨討伐がついでか
Subjugating the White Whale was secondary?
興味深いな
Intriguing.
Do you require assistance?
手が必要か？
必要だ
I do.
But...
けど―
Frankly, I didn't expect the hunt
would exact this kind of toll.
正直 ここまできついとは
思ってなかったからな
On top of that—
このうえ…
In that case, why not make use of this old man?
（ヴィルヘルム）
ならば この老く
使い潰されるがよろしいでしょう
Natsuki Subaru-dono,
ナツキ･スバル殿
こたびの討伐において―
with this subjugation,
it was because of you that
I was able to carry out my reason
この身が 今日まで
生きながらえてきた意味を―
全うすること
かないましたのは―
for living all this time.
貴殿あってのことです　感謝を
I thank you...
I thank you.
感謝を
私の全てにかけ 感謝を申し上げる
I thank you with all that I am!
やれたのは ヴィルヘルムさん
自身の力ですよ
It was your strength that made this possible, Wilhelm-san.
白鯨を倒そうって考えて
諦めないで戦って
You were so determined to defeat
the White Whale and fought relentlessly.
I'm not sure if it's my place to say this, but...
こう言っていいのか
分かんないんすけど―
おめでとうございます
あと お疲れ様でした
Congratulations.
And thank you for your service.
I believe you were able to do this
because you loved your wife like crazy.
奥さんをすっげー愛してたから
できたことだと思います
感謝を
I thank you...
その宝剣 今 しばらくは
卿が持っているがいい
You should hold on to that
treasured sword for a while.
In the days to come, being unarmed will do you little good.
この先 丸腰では役に立つまい
Yes, my lady. Thank you.
はっ ありがたく
Take Ferris and half of the uninjured.
フェリスと 無事な者の半数も
連れていくといい
20人といったところか
They should number about twenty.
（スバル）いいのか？
Are you sure?
恥知らずでありたくないと
言っただろ
I told you that I have no wish to be shameless.
And that I would respect you.
敬意を払うともな
Thank you.
（スバル）ありがとう
（レム）
どうしてですか？
Why?
だって体 動かにゃいでしょ？
You cannyot move, right?
As a user of healing magic,
I cannot let you push yourself further!
治癒術師として これ以上の
無理はさせられません
レムちゃんはお留守番
You'll stay behind—
でも うっ…
But...
H-Hey, careful!
危ねえって
頼むから フェリスの言うとおり
あんまりムチャすんなよ
Please obey Ferris, and don't overdo it.
I shall not.
（レム）
イヤなんです 苦しいんです
耐えられないんです
It hurts too much... I cannot bear it.
When you're in trouble,
スバルくんが困っている時―
I want to be the first to reach out to you.
誰よりも先に手を差し伸べるのは
レムでありたい
That is all I want! So please...
それだけが レムの望みなんです
ですから…
In that case, you don't have to worry.
（スバル）
それなら 心配なんかいらねえよ
俺はもう ずっとお前に救われてる
You've already saved me so many times.
（スバル）
ここに来るまで どんだけお前に
支えられたと思ってんだ
Don't you realize how much
you've done for me up till now?
I want you to help me from now on too.
これからも お前には
助けてもらいたい
So, this time, leave everything to me.
だから 今だけは全部任せろ
これからも レムを隣に
置いてくれますか？
After this, you'll still keep me by your side?
俺のほうから土下座で頼むぜ
I'm the one who should be begging you to.
言質 取りました
もう引っこめられませんよ
I shall take that as a promise.
You cannot back out now.
It'll be okay, Rem.
大丈夫だ レム
I'll find a way to take care of everything!
全部丸ごと 俺が
どうにかしてきてやる
俺は お前の英雄だ
I'm your hero!
その１歩を踏むと そう決めたんだ
I've decided to take that first step!
So don't you worry about a thing!
だから何も心配いらない
鯨狩りもやってのけた―
I managed to pull off the whale hunt.
お前の英雄は
超 鬼がかってんだろうが
Right now, your hero is demoniacally possessed.
Subaru-kun...
スバルくん
All right!
はい
レムの英雄は 世界一です
My hero is the greatest in the world!
Man, you really got all
the good parts back there, y'know?
ああ それにしても―
♪～
団長 ミミもミミも
Captain... Mimi too! Mimi too!
I did super-duper good!
ミミも 超すごー頑張った！
Didn't you almost die?
死にかけてたんじゃねえのかよ
つーか 弟が
あんだけ消耗してたのに―
Also, your brother was exhausted.
How do you have so much energy?
お前は どーして
そんな元気なの
Hetaro's just a baby. He's weak.
ヘータローは貧弱 軟弱
Really, it's so pathetic...
まったくもう 情けなーい
鯨退治の後半 ワイは
あんましやったけど―
Later in the battle with the Whale, I didn't get much done,
心配せんでくれや
but don't you worry.
My lady asked me for a favor, after all.
ちゃんと お嬢に
頼まれとるからなあ
In the real battle comin' up,
I'll show ya what I've got.
このあと 本命のほうで
活躍したるわ
The real battle? What do
you think I'm trying to do here?
（スバル）
本命って… お前
俺が何しようとしてるか…
You're takin' on the Witch Cult, right?
魔女教と 事構えるんやろ？
Never underestimate
the merchant information network.
商人の情報網 甘く見んことやな
Ah, here they come.
と… 来たか
ワイら傭(よう)兵団の
もう半分や
That's half of our mercenary team.
半分？
Half?
Half of 'em were sent to block the road,
もともと 半分は
鯨狩りやのうて―
instead of fightin' the Whale.
街道の封鎖を
担当しとったからな
They're going to help us too?
そいつらも
手伝ってくれんのか
そっちは 誰が
引っ張ってんだ？
Who's leading them?
My younger brother, Tivey!
ミミの弟の
ティビーがやってる
You have another younger brother?
まだ 弟いんのか
I'm really curious to know if
he's more like you or Hetaro.
お前に似てんのか
ヘータローに似てんのかが―
すっげー気になるんだが
（ミミ）ヘヘッ おーい！
Hey!
Why is he with them?
（スバル）何で あいつが…
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble
that  Defies
Despair
A  Gamble